- They don't have that, who don't have that, who don't?
(upbeat music)
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Oh yeah, you got it.
I was gonna tell you what you have to do with this.
- That's the situation.
- I remember the homework.
- Welcome everybody to Drop us a Line.
- Look who it is, look who it is.
- Special edition, it's Anna's first episode back
on Drop us a Line,
which is now by the way the main thing we do, Anna.
- Everything else is a front for Drop us a Line, okay?
- This is the heroin behind the scenes.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Grocery shop, cool.
- So, so welcome.
- Thank you.
- Back, right, cut.
Welcome to Drop us a Line, our audience feedback show.
My name's Andrew Hunter Murray.
I'm here with Anna Tajinsky and James Harkin.
- Hi Andy.
- Hi guys.
- Hello.
- We've had some fantastic emails.
- That way.
- I'm not even exaggerating.
So we're gonna start off with just a section,
one off section, the return of Anna,
because lots of people have been writing in.
- That's nice, because when you first came on the podcast,
when you came back after your break,
the first thing you said is,
is there not gonna be like a special intro for me?
- Starting with fact number one, it's Anna Tajinsky.
- Just strip my facts straight,
or a little welcome back to me, Andrew.
- No.
- Come here and be called that.
- What the fuck?
- Be the factor.
- She wants to welcome back Anna, Andrew.
- Like a little speech or something.
- Welcome back Anna, it's been awful without you.
- I know, I've heard the episodes.
(laughing)
- Laya.
- The rather full my auntie though.
We're doing the intro three weeks late.
- I've been saving it up,
because there have been so many nice comments.
So let's have a few.
- Great.
- See if you can spot the theme of these comments.
- Okay.
- Sarah writes, "Love the podcast,
and looking forward to Anna's return,
so that she can whip you boys back into shape."
- Frank Cardinali writes, "Just wondering,
if you three are fearful of Anna's reaction
to what has become of the podcast in her absence."
- Fortunately I've never listened to it.
- I love it, but it does have a feeling
of the kids running rampant while mum's been away.
Theo Warren, welcome back Anna,
please get these guys back in line.
Anthony, can't wait to hear Anna back on the show.
Brackets, you guys are great,
but after a while the class needs a teacher.
- Wow.
- Okay, wait a second.
Look, I thought this is gonna be a big Anna's
so great fest, but I've been called a mum and a teacher.
- It's very, Anna is the disciplinarian.
- Right.
- Is what the lesson has been getting over the last 12 years.
Don't know how you've got that.
- 'Cause I thought myself as the chilled out
of fun-loving clown.
- Oh no.
(laughing)
But a correction from Didry Cooper, okay.
The podcast blurb in the Apple Podcast player
referred to Anna as a prodigal podcaster.
- Oh yeah.
- I saw that.
- Prodigal means spending money or resources
freely and recklessly, which is what the prodigal son did.
- Yeah.
- The story in the Bible, he spent all his money
and he had to come back and--
- I saw the blurb.
It angered me as well, Didry, don't get me wrong.
I felt like it wasn't a good start for me to open my return
by sending a furious WhatsApp message on our production group,
but yes, prodigal refers to the habits of the son who returns,
not the returning.
- Sure.
But I was merely using it as a metaphor
for you, so people would know that you did something similar
to what the son did, which was return.
- Yes.
- No, I get that, I get that.
- But I think also you are wasteful and extravagant.
- Yeah, that's actually what James meant secretly.
- That's why I've had to come back to the show.
I didn't want to.
- Right.
Thanks, but no thanks.
Which I think you might have coined, Anna.
- So I think it sounds like me.
(laughing)
- It sounds a bit polite for you, really true.
Well, congratulations Rafael Alvarez.
Had an idea for a new tier of Club Vish.
- Okay, that's nice.
- So we've got a dual citizenship, plenty more fish,
and then friend of the podcast.
Rafael is pitching "So of the podcast."
For an exorbitant amount of money,
members can claim one of a limited number
of foes of the podcast to curate or fight.
Haven't worked out the details.
A few examples to get it going.
Mark Twain, Adolf Hitler, Zoe Williams,
the guardian writer.
- Do we have FIFA Zoe Williams?
- She wrote a piece asking why we're such bros of this podcast.
- And it was, I think, even if you disagree with that piece,
I think Hitler and Mark Twain.
That's not--
- Hit the Mark Twain and Zoe.
- What a weird dinner party.
- And the Treaty of Versailles.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Greg Wallace, of course.
(laughing)
The podcast.
- He was for a small amount of time.
- See, we mentioned it a few times as a father of the podcast.
- Did we call it before or after he became a co-operator
or someone else?
- Yeah, exactly.
- Nothing yet.
(laughing)
- For bonus, invective, people in this tier
can hear the uncensored clip in which Anna says,
"Which country has the ugliest men?"
And all the one in which Dan says,
"Which celebrity rejected a chance to meet Buzz Aldrin
"because they weren't a fan of space."
- Yeah, there's been a few of those reductions over the years.
- Yeah.
- But the thing to know is that I delete the original.
- So you can never go onto my hard drive
and find out who those celebrities are
because I delete them.
- That's good.
- Just in case someone steals my laptop,
slowly so they can find out which celebrity is not into space.
- Which country has the ugliest men?
It's so weird, I really want to have access to that file.
So I know who I think has the ugliest men.
- Yeah.
- It must have been.
I wouldn't have redacted it if it was a country
that we would never play it, right?
- Right.
- Oh, well, that limits it.
- I see.
- I feel like how we'd only do it if it was like,
Wales or something, so when we might play it, you might.
- It's not even a country, though.
Moving on, that's a joke.
People of Wales.
- Let's go on to, whoo, let's move on.
- Just a joke.
It's just a joke.
- Yeah.
To a bonus bream.
- Oh yeah.
- But it's also a get yourself off the hook.
- Oh, I'm not familiar with it, he's gone in.
- Okay, bonus bream is where we get extra information
about something that we said in the podcast.
Getting yourself off the hook is where we've made a mistake
and Andy tells us about it.
- Yeah.
- But you may be able to get yourself off the hook, if it's.
- It's worth saying that all of these names
have lots of subnames that mean the same thing,
or sometimes the same name is two different things.
- I'm sad that I missed all the brain storming sessions.
- There was no brain storming, there was one bream involved.
- Yeah, I feel weird, James, I don't know how you feel about it.
I feel weird like I'm presenting, drop us a line too, Anna,
and I feel a bit nervous.
- I'm not surprised, you do, with good reason.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you're just in the, you're offstead, I think.
And I'm a teacher who's like been whossing around
for a long time, we haven't had that measure for measure.
- I'm just saying, if you thought it wasn't fun
being called a teacher, you've now gone to an offstead.
- I know, the one who fires the teachers.
- Right.
- And we've been dealing with a manageable class size of two,
but I've still screwed it all up, I would say.
- Okay, Jamie writes, "I write in the confidence
"that your apocas to appreciate extremely pedantic corrections."
- Fair enough.
- "In your most recent episode, it was stated
"that neither Oliver nor Richard Cromwell
"could have observed the Chinese steam car."
- I believe it was you who said that, and it was me who said that.
While this is true, 'cause it was in the 1680s.
While this is true of Oliver,
Richard Cromwell could in fact have observed it.
He reigned as Lord Protector for less than a year,
but then resigned and lived in exile
until the age of 85, dying in 1712.
And we've mentioned this before,
he was the longest-lived head of state
until Queen Elizabeth II.
- And did he go and live in China?
(all laughing)
- That's right.
Hey, here's the fun thing I read.
- This is bonus cream from me.
- Lucky.
- Who's the first European that you can think of who went to China?
- Marco Polo.
- Do you know, he wasn't often kind of, obviously,
there was other people who went even as far back as ancient Greek,
some people went to China.
But Marco Polo's dad and his uncle both went to China.
- No way.
- He wasn't even the first Polo to go to China.
- Yeah. - That was really good.
- Isn't that amazing?
- They must have been so pissed off with him
when he got the book claiming he was a Nepo explorer.
- I should have known, 'cause in his memoirs,
he calls his dad drunk from a beach, saying,
"Please find me out of here."
(all laughing)
- Here's a bonus cream from Peter Blurm.
- Oh yeah.
- In a recent episode, you noted,
"Earth is the only place with plate tectonics
"and that they thus may be necessary for life, right?"
- Interesting.
- Did you know there is another hypothesis
which suggests that life is actually required
for plate tectonics, (all laughing)
because little life is so abundant,
small like microorganisms,
that it creates things like mud and limestone,
and that sort of lubricates the plates,
and that might kick start the kind of tectonics we now have.
What a theory.
- It sounded silly, but when you explain it,
you explain that you're not just saying
that a human one day said, "Earthquakes!"
and it happened, then it makes sense, actually.
- It does.
- I love that all modern earth and rock are all made of animals.
I always love that the reason chalk is white
is just 'cause it's skeletons.
The white cliffs of Dover is all just dead things.
- Yeah, as a boring old teacher, you would like chalk.
- You can actually have an interactive whiteboard.
(all laughing)
- That you've drawn on with permanent marker and final stake.
- Oh, rodeo clan number one.
- Okay, rodeo clan, that is.
- Well, what are you thinking of?
- I was actually here for this.
- I rodeo clan game.
I really hoped it might have blown over in the nine months.
I've been gone, but...
- You don't think there's blown over.
- You've had any big moshettes as blown into where we are.
(all laughing)
- All right, well, I didn't know it had turned into a segment.
- It started to a segment.
- What segment would it be, do you think?
What does it mean?
- It's something where we say,
"Well, what's this thing?"
- And a million people write in and say,
"I'm so insulted, I'm this thing."
- Brilliant. - Kind of.
- Yeah.
- Just getting a lot of emails about the something.
- So what's the rodeo clan this week?
- I'm gonna start with Laura Falkiner.
I'm writing it off the back of the later's little fish
to let you know that rag-and-bone men,
brackets people are still going strong.
- Rag-and-bone people.
- They're not going strong.
(all laughing)
- I don't know the context for where are they going strong.
So what happened was, I mentioned that when I was growing up,
we had rag-and-bone men, but in fairness,
they're not always men, but they're always known
as rag-and-bone men in where I came from.
By any way, we start had them growing up
and even into my 20s, we had them.
And I mean, was very surprised by that.
- Yeah, and well, I've been schooled thoroughly.
Sheffield 2020 to 2022.
Laura Falkiner has seen evidence of them,
calling for any old iron.
And she says, "James isn't old, he's just northern."
(all laughing)
- That sounds like someone saying something
when they look at my face.
(all laughing)
- Oh, you look old.
- No, I'm not old, I'm just northern.
(all laughing)
- Rob Hardesty says I remember them
on horse-drawn carts in the late '70s and early '80s
in Rochdale, so maybe it was a northern thing.
Annie Self lives in the small rural town of Bungay.
- Oh yeah.
- Oh, and it's Bungay, not Bungay, sorry.
- Famous for having lots of Satanists,
not that I've ever met one, not that you know Annie.
- Not really, are they like the Mason's or something?
- You don't know, I mean, you wouldn't mention it,
but probably some people mention it as soon as they meet.
You're high, I'm a Satanist, actually.
- Oh yeah, I don't know.
- There's some people probably keep it.
- Like a vegan, how do you know something's a Satanist?
They'll tell you as they pull out your twitching heart
and rub it on a wall to open a portal to nether realms.
- But Annie says we have some guys come round
and again in a flatbed truck shouting, "Any old iron?"
- Which is the proper.
- Annie old iron, Annie old iron, Annie old iron.
- See, that's a cockney song, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- And Lisa Cirties has a slightly related thing
'cause she remembers them from Hartley Pool.
- It is going strongly, that sounds like I take it back.
- But Lisa moved to Hartley Pool and says
we have some of the last sea colors.
Twice a day, they drive a truck out to the beach
when the tide is out.
Gather the coal that has settled on the beach
with shovels and load it into their truck every day.
So that's it.
- I think they're turds, aren't they?
- They burn the same, they burn sweeten the right.
And then Lisa says there are many places in the world
where colder posits wash up on the beach.
Yeah, I think not.
But Hartley Pool is one of them.
- No way.
- It sluffs off and washes onto the beach.
- Sluffs off from nearby.
- From the coal, the sea's the nearby seam of coal
which is exposed at the seabed.
- Wow.
- So it's just, that's fantastic.
- Daniel Painter says, in Little Fish,
you had a quick think of who is the most
atted modern day leader.
- Oh yeah, that's good.
- Does the Pope count?
- Oh, he has to.
- Yeah, he's winning, isn't he?
- What constitutes a hat?
- Are you thinking Skullcats for a chief rabbi or something?
- I'm thinking Skullcats, I'm thinking like Yata Arifats.
- You know what, that's what I said.
And they mocked me, I've not been up to date.
- With my world leaders.
- He's not old, he's just Palestinian.
(laughing)
- But somewhere else has similar cultural markers as I do.
- Do you think his son would do better
if he always wore a top hat?
- Yeah.
- Oh, without doubt?
- He would, wouldn't he?
- Anyway, look, we've got, we've got 50 pages of evil.
- Jesus Christ, Andy, 'cause I have to leave today.
- You think you do, you go, when I say you go,
not when the bell says you go.
(laughing)
- Right, let's come on to both fins.
- Oh, I'm so glad this is still in.
- Yeah, experts, on stuff, who've written in?
To school us.
Mendel Skullski, what name?
- If he good, if he ran a ski school.
(laughing)
- Who says, I run a small ski school on the,
just thought I'd offer a slight correction
on the kelp highway hypothesis.
- Okay, so this was the theory that humans moved down
the American coast to follow the seaweed.
- The West Coast where there was lots of seaweed.
I think it was James who mentioned in passing
that people were surviving in transit by it in kelp.
- I think it was you.
- I think it was me.
- It was you.
- It's quite likely that some kelp was being consumed,
but more likely it was all manner of seafood, fair point.
(laughing)
Kelp houses lots of animal species, basically.
- Oh yeah, I see that, but there's kelp, there's other stuff.
- Yeah.
- But he says, in case you're interested,
we, future ecologies, spent three whole episodes talking
about kelp and its ecological and social entanglements.
- Is this an ad for this guy's podcast?
- Well, I deduct that.
- I suppose so, yeah.
- Unless they pay us.
- Okay, but it's mental then has a great fact,
which is the reason I wanted to come to this.
It's the fact that sea otters were restored to the West Coast
of North America after having been driven nearly
to extinction right sea otters, they're almost wiped out.
And they were restored not for ecological restoration,
but to evacuate them from impending US nuclear testing
in Alaska.
- Oh.
- That's just a cool fact about that.
- Yeah, nice.
- Right, I don't know what section this is.
Oh, it says "Misc" at the top here.
- Does everything need to be a section?
Yeah, surely we should just have it.
It does.
- Fishelanias.
- No, it's Mussolanias.
- Oh, is that?
- Mussolanias.
- Really, did you just think of, or is it?
- No.
- No, but when I said it the first time,
I had just thought of it.
But then I wrote it down.
I've never remembered it since then.
(laughing)
But I'm writing it down again now.
- There's a lot of writing stuff down in this podcast now.
- Okay, cool.
- How's the inspection going, Anna?
- It's time writing a lot of stuff down in here as well, I need.
- Okay, here's a question for you.
Hailey Thompson, long time listener here.
I'm planning my first trip to the UK, specifically to London.
- Okay.
- I often listen to older episodes of Fish while I'm working
and I've been jotting down places to go that you've all mentioned
as possible destinations in anticipation.
- Anywhere else apart from weatherspins?
Is this funny to go?
- It's not all weatherspins, she says.
(laughing)
I'm planning to go to Dishroom.
- Oh yeah.
- Nice.
- The weatherspins of the East.
That caught me thinking.
(laughing)
- I love that marketing idea.
- Yeah.
- That got me thinking, if you could all pick a spot
that you'd put on a fish tour of London or the UK,
what would it be and why?
So I thought I'd put you on the spot.
- I like those next to Clear Patches Needles.
Those, is it the two lions?
- Sphinxes.
- Sphinxes, yeah, where Dan said you can put your finger
in the bum holes.
- Yeah.
- That was a good moment of fish.
- That was great.
And actually, once you've finished there,
'cause that's on the embankment of the river
and you should go to spend a lot of time near the river,
go to the Basil Jet Memorial, which is by embankment tube,
and it's just quite rosy there, but it's just in a wall,
and it's Joseph Basil Jet who built the sewers,
and it's on land that he reclaimed from the river.
What's your pick, Anna?
- Oh, I would say go to the,
do you know what we did that episode on Thomas Hardy?
Thomas Hardy's grave, so Thomas Hardy designed the graveyard
in King's Cross, was it at the time?
- Yeah.
- But then it all got moved,
and now there's kind of a monument to it
just behind King's Cross,
and it's this amazing kind of tree
with all these old gravestones sticking out of it.
- And it's spiraling around this.
- It's spiral, yeah, that's pretty cool.
- Yeah, that's pretty good.
- Paul is corner of Westminster Rabbit,
of Westminster Rabbit. - All that.
- Tower of London.
- I mean, they're just places.
- Some Paul's Cathedral?
- Yeah.
- Literally, they will be on your first page of Google.
- King's Palace.
- London Eye. - London Eye.
- Today's it's London Eye.
- If you can get out of the city, Stonehenge is a good day.
(laughing)
- Shrek's adventure, if you can't.
- I tell you why, if you're coming from North America,
and you've got a bit of time to spare France, it's nice.
(laughing)
- London Zoo has a lot of animals from all over the world.
You don't need to go anywhere once you've been there.
- Yeah.
- So there's a big friend.
- I mean, genuinely, so we live in a city of jewels.
- Sure.
- Wondon, that's what I call it, 'cause it's wonderful, you know?
(laughing)
- Chaziel.
- This is a bit called Bad Romance.
'Cause we've had romance, ROE.
- Yeah, I got it, yeah.
- Fish eggs.
- I don't know if you know this one's about Lady Gaga.
- This is the fact, right, Lady Gaga.
- Yeah.
- Alex Dean writes, "As a long-time listener of the show,
"I've always hoped to one day work of fact
"from the podcast organically into real-life conversation.
"Unfortunately due to my terrible memory, I've never managed it
"until the other day.
"While on a date, we walked past a model train shop."
- Chaziel.
- It's lovely, like the days.
(laughing)
- As we stopped to look in the window.
- I suddenly remembered.
- Come back, come back.
Darling, come back.
We need to look in this window for a bit.
- I suddenly remembered a fact from the show
that I was delighted to finally deploy naturally
in everyday life.
I turned and explained to the Cole.
(laughing)
The Cole used in Model Railway Exhibitions
is actually just small (laughing)
to grasp that piece of some Cole.
- I'm Zida, I'm Mary Kat.
(laughing)
- She replied that that was one of the dullest things
she had ever heard.
(laughing)
- I don't know what to say, Alex.
It's how you tell 'em.
(laughing)
- If she could get in touch with me,
I think we might get along pretty well.
- Isn't that wonderful?
- That's just lovely.
- Gratislations, Alex.
- Good luck getting back on the app, shall we?
- You're first to tell that.
(laughing)
- She's out there.
Ah, there we go.
Logan writes, "This is a thing
"is a sort of micro-clown, there's a little clown."
- Okay.
- I'm listening to the drop of the line,
the episode in which people have written in about
having a difficult time telling
Dan and Andy's voices apart.
I'm sure the inbox is bulging
with even more people contributing their thoughts
on the matter, sort of, actually.
A few people have written in saying,
yeah, can't tell Dan and Andy apart.
Logan says, "I'm visually impaired
"in a way that affects central visual acuity."
So Logan relies on voice and stature to identify anyone.
Logan works as a 9-1-1 dispatcher.
So 9-9-9 for British listeners.
- Thanks.
- And I've got, (laughing)
and I've got very good at distinguishing voices, right?
I work with dozens of units throughout the week
and I can identify most of them by voice,
having never seen them.
- Great.
- I've listened to this podcast almost every day since 2019
and I still can't tell Dan and Andy's voices apart.
- Isn't that weird?
- Wow, he's-- - They don't even sound the same
and I can tell that it's two different people talking,
but I can't for the life of me identify who is speaking.
- What?
- I know.
- Yeah.
- That sort of, so it implies they sound different to you,
but what they're saying is sort of so non-memorable
that you haven't managed to peg it to their name.
- Or memorable in the same way.
- Yeah.
- They just say the same sort of stuff all the time.
- Yeah, exactly.
- That's a bit of a slam, isn't it Andy?
- Well, on someone.
(laughing)
On someone, on someone, yeah.
I mean, no one has a problem identifying your voice, James.
- Yeah, that's so interesting.
- They do mistake you and I when they see pictures of us.
- Yeah.
- And whose voice is whose?
- That's true.
- By think my actual voice, they would know it was James,
but they might not know what I look like.
- Oh, yeah.
- This is Andy speaking now.
- Oh, that is not here.
- Yeah.
- That's why he's not--
- It's this easy as today, Logan, yeah, yeah.
Right, come on.
Get yourself off the hook.
Dave Wang writes, "Life long bilingual,"
and that's not just a boast,
because also, "Fisherless in the Since Day One,"
Dan's Chinese name should be Shribo,
which literally sounds like Shriver,
and means handsome uncle.
- Ah, not uncle egg.
- Because Dan said his Chinese name was Uncle Egg,
and then Dan texted me separately saying,
"Oh man, I misspoke on fish."
So apologies if you get lots of emails.
We've had one.
(laughing)
I said my Chinese name is Uncle Egg, which it is,
but I didn't realize I just said my surname bit.
So it's Shibo Dan in Chinese.
- Oh yeah, Dan does mean Egg,
'cause Dan Dan meets testicles.
- Oh yeah.
- His full name is thanks, she Uncle Boa Egg Dan.
Sorry if the inbox gets flooded.
(laughing)
- Dan, flattering yourself.
A number of people who listen to what you're saying.
(laughing)
Did you know that more than half of the people
on this earth are fluent in at least two languages?
- Oh, that's amazing.
- That's good, isn't it?
- It's so cool.
- It's good, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Western might people aren't great on that,
but most of the world doing well.
A lot of Western might people who don't have English
as a first language are great on that.
- They are also very good, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Just English speaking people out there.
Moa's actor from India here.
I was listening to episode three, five, one.
No such thing as pop charts for bagpipers,
in which you mentioned anyone, anyone, do you remember?
The world's longest cake.
(laughing)
- Oh yeah, I do remember that.
- Was it in Romania or was that the world's longest sausage?
- Kerala, South India.
- Kerala, okay.
- The record was broken in Kerala.
I happen to have moved to Kerala for work.
There is a bakery, a few hundred meters from my house,
which participated in the event.
- Wow.
- The cake was 5.3 kilometers long.
Not 6.5, as you said.
- What?
- So we got the cake wrong by...
- How did we do that?
- A kilometer.
- 'Cause it's not like we looked at it
and estimated the length.
(laughing)
We will have got that information from Guinness, I guess,
normally.
- I don't know, I don't know what.
Maybe someone ate a kilometer of it before that.
(laughing)
- Come on, something good cake.
- Yeah, I don't think it's provided sources.
And I haven't checked.
So it'll have to be one of those mysteries.
- Yeah, we'll never know.
- Final clown, bombs dropping and the whistling noise they make.
I think I slightly screwed up the explanation
of the...
- Doppler effects.
Jonathan, commander, Royal Navy.
- Cool.
- What an unusual surname.
(laughing)
- It says, if it's falling on you,
you might hear the increasing note,
but you won't be able to tell anyone about it.
But if it's dropping on someone else,
then the mile away, the pitch will drop down
in the final stages,
'cause it's sliding down the opposite side of a triangle to you.
So this is the sound that survivors here is relevant.
I'm gonna paraphrase and be brief,
because we've had so many long emails
about the Doppler effect.
- Oh, how do we?
- And I'll cheerfully just roll over and say, yeah, sorry.
- Wait, why don't I sound what was...
- Also, I said pitch and frequency,
and I confused those two,
and the whole thing was a cluster mistake.
- It was a real cluster mistake.
- Peter Drake, listening to your recent episode
of "Avolving Spurma Setty".
- Oh, yeah.
- I wondered when you'd get to Moby Dick,
a book famous for being comically obsessed with this fluid.
- Yeah.
- Andy, you got there first with the line "Eat-it-ish-male",
but I'm afraid you misstepped.
The harpooner was not "ish-male",
but his bunkmate Quique,
I am sure many people have pointed this out.
(laughing)
No, I'm gonna...
No, on this occasion,
I'm gonna stick out for myself.
(laughing)
- Come on.
- I think, if I had said "Eat-it-quee-quee".
(laughing)
I would have received black faces.
- When you said that in a theater of 3,000 people,
you might get one English teacher pissing themselves
and has made his life, he's thrilled.
- That's it.
- But genuinely, I could have said,
I could have said "A-hab",
but that would have been another valid joke
'cause people know about Captain A-hab,
but they were a team effort on doing that well.
I think it's fine to say the most famous,
call me "ish-male",
other than those three words of the book.
Just, yeah, so reject it.
- Important to be right.
- I think we've done a whole section on "Moby Dick" once.
- Yeah.
- So I would suggest to go back and find that
because it was a good idea.
- Was it a goody?
- Yeah, it was.
- Mikey Giggler.
- Do you know what this is, Hannah?
- No.
- It's where someone writes into us saying,
"I can't believe you didn't make a joke
that you could have made on the episode."
- Wait, Mike Giggler?
- It's a reference to private, I think.
- Yeah.
- Okay, you know?
- I thought it was just a name of a correspondent
that we had. - No.
- This week's Mike Giggler is Chris Locke from Farnham.
- Uh huh.
- I cannot believe that you discussed the usage
of whale meat during World War II rationing
and forgot to mention the song "Vira Lin Song",
specifically encouraging the population of the UK
to eat more of it.
You mean whale meat again?
(laughing)
Regardless of the place or time.
Yeah, very good.
- No, no, no, no.
- Nice one, Chris, you got us.
- Yeah, it's a good one, actually.
Quite often, these are not very good.
- No, that's much better than you.
That's much better than the usual.
I can't believe you.
That's lovely.
I'm gonna steal that.
- Yeah, yeah.
Vindancation.
We've had a Vindancation.
- Oh, this is where we've indicated something
that Dunn said.
- That's right.
- I can tell.
And I can tell how long you brainstormed that part as well.
- We had so many emails about this.
Tim Groves is a great example of this.
You know, I'm just gonna do his email.
I'm gonna take a punt here on being
one of a legion of listeners, correct,
writing in about this.
I have just been listening to the episode of Little Fish
from the 25th of May, while on a train to London
to try a vegan fish taco, brackets, not important.
Clothes, brackets.
And I was shocked to hear Andy and Anna ridicule Dan
for his vaguely remembered story
about a man swallowing a Faberier egg.
(laughing)
I also remembered this story and a light search yielded
the following BBC News.
Police recovered $19,000 Faberier egg swallowed
by New Zealand man.
- Okay.
- It was a an octopus-y-themed egg.
- It was a James Bond film.
- I know James Bond film.
- Yeah, now I've seen that.
- It was a plant-dependent, I think.
And it was laid about a week after he swallowed it.
- Okay, so it wasn't a false.
I think the problem was we didn't mention
that it was a pendant and actual Faberier eggs.
I mean, he worked this New Zealander
would literally look like a Kiwi.
(laughing)
The enormous egg inside him.
- But Dan was right.
Someone had swallowed a Faberier thing.
- An octopus-y-themed Faberier.
- Yeah, I mean, I think maybe they branched out
from the original taste, but it's all for royalty.
- All right, I think I kind of assumed
that it probably was based in fact
because it would be an amazing thing
for Dan to have made up.
He's got a funny outbreak though.
- Yeah, but no, completely fair.
Like, I doubled down and I teased him again.
So I feel better if I haven't done it.
- Did you mess with him and apologize?
- No.
- Oh.
(laughing)
- Although the inbox has been flooded by it,
so actually I should do.
But I do the email, so it's fine.
- Why don't you, it's a camera.
Why don't you apologize to him now?
- Oh my God, what?
(laughing)
- It's like a hostage video.
- This is like Johnny Depp when he smuggled
with it.
- I could have blinks in the show that I need help.
Dan, I'm really sorry.
(laughing)
No, I'm sorry, Dan.
And I hope you listen to this.
- If anyone's been held hostage here,
it's not you, Andy.
- Okay.
- I'll choose this.
- What time are you on?
- Dave Rule.
- Is this a segment?
- Or okay.
(laughing)
- Dave Rule says, "I wanted to follow up
and let you know how thrilled I am.
This has become such a phenomenon in its own right.
And how much joy it brings me
to hear Dan and James Squirm
whenever one of these comes up unexpectedly."
Dave Rule sent the first ever thing
that sounds like its name for one obvious reason,
but it's actually named after a person
with an amusingly apt name.
- Okay, good.
What?
- And what was his one?
- This was October 2025.
He sent a list of things unexpectedly named after people,
including also, I mean, some classics,
Main Street in San Francisco,
named for Charles Main, Snowflake, Arizona, Taco Bell,
named after Glen Bell.
- Okay.
- We've had seven more pages of this stuff
since the last drop.
I don't know what to do.
It's what the people want.
It's just what people want.
- This needs to be a whole new podcast
that we don't do.
(laughing)
- Ah, no.
You almost contractually applies yourself
into something there.
- Yeah.
- Turn that full stop into a comment pretty fast.
(laughing)
Dan Painter, Penny's game about flipping a coin,
heads or tails, right?
Created by Walter Penny.
- Wow.
- Yeah, very good.
- Daniel Power, the suburb of Sydney,
called Wallstonecraft, right?
And I knew Mary Wallstonecraft was an important feminist
and I joked, imagine if it was just named after some dude
instead of her.
Well, it turns out that Wallstonecraft,
the Sydney suburb, was named not after the early feminist
and important historical figure, Mary Wallstonecraft,
it's named after a man, Edward Wallstonecraft,
who's really only known for moving to Australia
to escape the notoriety of his Aunt Mary.
- That's so good, really.
- Yeah, I think he was a big deal in his own right.
But yeah, anyway, I can sense the patient's running thin here.
So I'm just gonna keep salting them away for the book.
And when I'm on every till in every book shop
across the world.
- That Penny one is absolutely cracking.
- I know.
- This is really good, this should be a book.
- I don't encourage him for fuck's sake.
- Oh, it should be a book.
- It should be.
- We can spend six months writing it.
- Six months.
- Oh, are we doing an abridged version?
- I'll tell you, this is a 10 year project.
The book is called a thousand and one things that are named.
Have you not, have you not heard that?
- What's the book called a thousand and one thing that are?
- Well, this is an excellent point.
- No, no.
- It's, it's something.
There's the main header.
And then the subtitle is a thousand and one,
the book of a thousand and one things.
I'm still working on it.
That you think were named for a very obvious reason.
But were in fact named after a person
with an amusingly apt name.
- I think that's very catchy.
- Yeah, it's been proposed by Thomas Grove's bond
that this be called the Hunter Index.
Not named after the hunt for these names,
but after Andrew Hunter Murray.
- Lovely.
- Yeah.
- All right, look.
We'll do more of these next time.
Thank you so much for everyone who said one thing.
I'm sorry we didn't get all of them.
The final closer goes to anonymous L, who says,
"I believe that I speak for myself when I say."
(laughing)
- It's funny, that I actually quite enjoy
the Inca here at Ramblings and the way Andrew Hunter
Murray runs the "Troppinson" live show.
Especially the section naming section
and the book of things that are named and all that.
There's already been over 50 minutes of discussion
on the actual facts on the podcast.
So not too sure why the others want to do more.
- Okay.
(laughing)
- A little trade secret.
They want to do less.
(laughing)
- We'll be over a chord every time.
I keep saying we'll be out within an hour
and we never are.
- A non-emissal.
- Yeah.
I think they didn't want their name in.
- No.
- But why would you with such a cleanest opinion?
(laughing)
- No, in the Roberts, we cut out of this show.
You know, you'll see.
- Yeah, who's that?
(laughing)
- We're wrapping up.
- We're done.
How's the inspection going now?
- I would say special measures coming out for you.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Thank you for listening and watching.
If you'd like to send in your stories
and your romance, good or bad, or your...
- What else have we done?
I've got a list of things in the comments
about the show that we've done.
- Spicy meat, your riddle roundabout, your secret squid.
- It doesn't have to fall into one of these
like weirdly crowbar categories.
- Seven squabbles.
- No, it could just be common squabbles.
(laughing)
- Send your Seven squabbles and then the music kicks in
and out we go and it's podcasted at qi.com.
Okay, thanks everybody.
Bye.
(upbeat music)